<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Ian Adams</title>
  <id>http://ijadams.github.io</id>
  <link href="http://ijadams.github.io" />
  <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2016-04-11T21:26:18-05:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, Ian Adams</rights>
  <author>
    <name>Ian Adams</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>The Roots of Music - Branding &amp; Identity</title>
      <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/2016/02/01/roots-branding/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being a member of a marching band since I was 12 years old, I was thrilled when the The Roots of Music asked me to work with them. ROM is a non-profit that focuses on providing music education, academic support, and mentorship for New Orleans youths. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since ROM first launched they have a identified with a seal that represented the organic mission of the organization. It served them well for their first few years, but as they grew and evolved they needed something that would be distinctive, easily consumed, and remembered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After drafting and designing an endless amount of different icons we felt accurately described the company&#39;s mission. The result is a logo and set of letters that picks up on the playful nature of ROM as well as the professionalism of the student musicians:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/roots.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Just for fun, here&#39;s an alternate version that will be used for apparel:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/roots-circle.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://ijadams.github.io/2016/02/01/roots-branding/</id>
      <updated>2016-02-01T06:57:51-06:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ian Adams</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>SERP Tool</title>
      <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/2015/05/04/serp-tool/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
The goal of this project was to create a user friendly solution to getting keyword rankings from Google. Search results are unique to the user - usually based on search history, geographic location, and other factors - but this tool would be a helpful way for people to see how their marketing efforts are effecting their SEO. I started out adapting a PHP library I found on Github in hopes of finding an automatic solution and it worked great until it was time to scale. Unfortunately, Google doesn&#39;t offer a search API and isn&#39;t really hip to people restricting automated requests. This makes it really hard to search for a large list of terms without burning through a ton of proxies.
 &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Ultimately, it ended up being better to go with a semi-automatic Chrome extension and user script. Even though the intial goal wasn&#39;t fully realized, I really learned a lot about how web scraping works and look forward to using these skills for some cool data oriented projects in the future!
 &lt;br /&gt;
Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ijadams/serp-chrome-ext&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Also check out the user script &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ijadams/serp-user-script&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://ijadams.github.io/2015/05/04/serp-tool/</id>
      <updated>2015-05-04T11:57:51-05:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ian Adams</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Milk</title>
      <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/2015/04/02/milk/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a fun project I did experimenting with jQuery and HTML5. The playbackRate property of the audio and video elements change as the cursor gets further away from the center of the window. All of the milk sounds were made using Text Edit and Audacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out here &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianjadams.com/milk&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://ijadams.github.io/2015/04/02/milk/</id>
      <updated>2015-04-02T11:57:51-05:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ian Adams</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Sandwich Web Art...</title>
      <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/2015/02/22/sandwich-art/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/img1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some fun stuff I did over the weekend. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianjadams.com/lilsubbies&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: After playing at SXSW in Austin for a week, I went and made this torta edition &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianjadams.com/lilsubbies/torta&quot;&gt;here!&lt;/a&gt; Also was messing around with the Paper JS animation library while I was thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianjadams.com/lilsubbies/cuban&quot;&gt;cubans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://ijadams.github.io/2015/02/22/sandwich-art/</id>
      <updated>2015-02-22T10:57:51-06:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ian Adams</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>CSV Formatter Built With Papa Parse JS</title>
      <link href="http://ijadams.github.io/2015/02/17/csv-formatter/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For this project, I wanted to automate a business process that I found particularly annoying at my old position. Hootsuite is a social media application that allows you to schedule social media posts in bulk and across different platforms. Our company was doing a lot of manual scheduling on HS, and not taking full advantage of the bulk uploading component that allows you to upload CSVs of posts. In order to increase efficiency, I decided to make a tool that would reformat our social media posts spreadsheets to conform to Hootsuite’s bulk uploader standards. This meant a lot of parsing of CSVs and nested arrays. I was able to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://papaparse.com&quot;&gt;PapaParse JS&lt;/a&gt;, which was extremely helpful and fast. Papaparse does a lot of cool stuff and coming from an Econometrics background, it’s a great way to parse data and display in it nice ways. Check out the code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ijadams/hsformatter&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the live demo &lt;a href=&quot;http://previewchanges.com/~iadams/twitter.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://ijadams.github.io/2015/02/17/csv-formatter/</id>
      <updated>2015-02-17T10:57:51-06:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Ian Adams</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
